Guide to the Peter H.L. and Edith Chang Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Peter H.L. and Edith Chang Papers,
1930s-2001
Zhang, Xueliang, 1898-
60 linear ft. (46 document boxes; 22 record cartons; 27 card file boxes; 2 mapcases).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY. 10027
6484240
MS#0210
Biographical Note
Peter Chang (his name also rendered as Zhang Xueliang, and Chang Hsueh-liang) was born in Manchuria in 1901 and died in Hawaii in 2001. After his father Chang Tso-lin Zhang Zuolin, a leading war-lord known as the Old Marshal, was assassinated in 1928 by the Japanese, Chang took his place as the Young Marshal, becoming one of the most powerful military figures in China.
In 1930 Chang became Deputy Commander in Chief of the Chinese Armed Forces. In 1933 he traveled to Europe. Upon his return to China, Zhou Enlai convinced him of the need for a united front between the Nationalist and Communist Chinese against Japan.
On December 4, 1936, Chiang Kai-shek, the Nationalist leader, met with Marshal Chang in Xian, ostensibly to plan a campaign against the Communists that was due to begin on December 12. Chang arrested Chiang Kai-shek, an event that became known around the world as the Xian incident. Two weeks later Chiang was released after agreeing to work with the Communists in fighting the Japanese.
After the Xian incident Marshal Chang might have chosen to join the Communists. Instead he surrendered to Chiang Kai-shek who placed him under house arrest. This was his status for the next fifty years, even after the Nationalists fled to Taiwan taking Chang with them. As he said in 1991 in his first interview after recovering his freedom, "It was a rebellion and I had to take responsibility for it".
During his long period of confinement on Taiwan, Marshal Chang lived comfortably in a house with an extensive garden selected by Chiang Kai-shek son, Chiang Ching-kuo, who succeeded his father as President of Taiwan. During this time Chang became a Baptist and spent many hours writing, reading the Bible, and studying history. The house was filled with paintings and calligraphy honoring the Chiang family, including a number that were drawn by Madame Chang Kai-shek. Many of these items are now at Columbia in the Chang Papers.
After his release Marshall Chang settled in Hawaii in 1995 with his second wife Yi Di Zhao, known as Edith Chang who predeceased him by one year. The daughter of a senior official, she had left her family while still in her teens to become his companion, later following him into exile on Taiwan. Her devotion so moved Chang's first wife Yu Feng-chih that she released him from his marriage vows.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, notes, documents, artwork, calligraphies, study materials, photographs published material, and clippings, detailing the various stages of the life of Peter and Edith Chang.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 10 series:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Manuscripts
Series III: Documents
Series IV: Study Notes
Series V: Diaries
Series VI: Art
Series VII: Printed Materials
Series VIII: Audio Visual
Series IX: Photographs
Series X: Personal Effects
Subjects
Chiang, Kai-shek, 1887-1975.; Zhang, Xueliang, 1898-; Zhang, Xueliang, 1898-; China--History--20th century.; China--History--Xi'an Incident, 1936.; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.; China--Foreign relations--Japan.; Generals--China.; Occupation
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 46-96. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Gift of Edith and Peter Chang, 1993
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Chiang, Kai-shek
    - Chiang, Kai-shek Chang’s Personal Album, (1 volume [68 pages and 4 loose pages] ) (Box 01, Folder 01)
      [Contents analyzed under names of correspondents. Pages numbered by RBML staff. ]
    - Chiang, Kai-shek [also as Jiang Jie-shi, Chiang Zhong-zheng] To Peter H. L. Chang, [Nanking] 7/1/[1937], (4 page, manuscript letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 02)
    - Chiang, Kai-shek To Peter H. L. Chang, [n.p.] 10/[n.m.]/[1937], (1 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 01)
      [SEE: Chang's Personal Album, page 1 [Box 1, Folder 1]]
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [n.p.] 9/11/ [Prior to 1946], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.06)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [n.p.] [1946], (3 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.07)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [Jingshang] 17/5[1947], (1 leaf autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.06)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [n.p., n.d.] [n.m.][1952], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.07)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [n.p.] 29/10/[1953], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.06)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [n.p.] 31/10/M43 [1954], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.01)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [n.p.] 21/12[1956], (1 leaf autograph letter (draft); 2 leaf autograph letter; 2 loose pages ) (Box 01, Folder 03.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [n.p.] 25/12/M45 [1956], (1 leaf autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [Taipei][1956], (1 page, autograph letter (draft, with clipping) ) (Box 01, Folder 03.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [Xinzhu] 31/10/[1957], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.03)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [n.p.] 31/10/[1959], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.06)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [n.p.] 30/10[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.06)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, Xiziwan 31/10[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.06)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [n.p., n.d.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.07)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang Kai-shek, [n.p., n.d.], (1 leaf autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 03.07)
  - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong [also as Mme Chiang Kai-shek, Song Mei-ling] To Peter H. L. Chang, Hangzhou 28/3/[1937], (1 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 04.01)
      [SEE: Chang’s Personal Album, page 2 [Box 1, Folder 1]]
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, [Nanking]7/10/[1937], (2 page, manuscript letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 04.01)
      [SEE: In Chang’s Personal Album, pages 3-4 [Box 1, Folder 1]]
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Chungking 29/7/1941, (1 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 04.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Nanking 15/11/1946, (4 page, typed letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 04.03)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 5/12/[1946], (2 leaf autograph letter (draft) ) (Box 01, Folder 04.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Nanking 8/5/1947, (3 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 04.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Jingshang] 17/5/[1947], (3 leaf, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 04.04)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Nanking 24/8/1947, (2 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 04.05)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Nanking 19/9/1947, (4 page, autograph letter signed, and clipping ) (Box 01, Folder 05.01)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Jingshang] 5/10/[1947], (2 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 05.01)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Nanking 30/12/1947, (3 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 05.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] [1947], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 05.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Nanking 15/4/1948, (3 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 05.03)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 12/5/[1948], (1 leaf, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 05.03)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Chiang, Mei-ling Soong, To H. L. Chang [n.p.] March 5, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 03.04)
    - Edith Chang To Chiang, Mi-ling Soong, North Hollywood, California: April 10, 1950, (1 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 37, Folder 03.04)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 11/4/1950, (3 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 05.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] 16/4/[1950], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 05.04)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 21/4/1950, (3 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 05.05)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 23/9/1950, (1 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 06.01)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 3/2/1951, (1 page, typed letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 06.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 21/4/1951, (1 page, typed letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 06.03)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] 24/4/1951, (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 06.03)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] 5/5/[1951], (3 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 06.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 27/11/1951, (2 page, typed letter signed, and card with envelope ) (Box 01, Folder 06.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] 29/12/[1951], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 06.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] 8th [n.m.]/[1951], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 06.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 25/1/1952, (2 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 06.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] 28/1/[1952], (1 leaf autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 06.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] 11/3/1952, (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 07.01)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 30/3/1952, (1 page, typed letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 07.01)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 30/4/1952, (3 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 07.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] 2/5/[1952], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 07.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 26/5/1952, (1 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 07.03)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 14/2/[1953], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 07.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 14/2/[1953], (1 leaf, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 07.04)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 29/4/1953, (1 page, typed letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 07.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] 6/5/1953, (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 07.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] [21]/[9]/M42 [1953], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 08.01)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 4/6/M43 [1954], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 08.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 24/10/M43 [1954], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 08.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 25/10/1954, (2 page, typed letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 08.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] 30/10/1954, (2 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 08.04)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 8/3/1955, (1 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 08.05)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei [n.d.]/[3]/[1955], (1 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 08.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] [22]/[3]/[1956], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 09.01)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] [17/5/1956], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 09.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] 25/12/M45 [1956], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 09.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei [n.d.] [1956], (1 page, manuscript letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 09.01)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 25/7/[1957], (1 page, typed letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 09.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] 28/7/1957, (2 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 09.04)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 5/12/1957, (1 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 09.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Xiziwan]7/12/M46[1957], (1 leaf autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 09.05)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei, 19/12/1957, (1 page, typed letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 10.01)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 14/4/1958, (1 page, typed letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 10.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, New York 14/12/1958, (2 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 10.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 2/7/1959, (1 page, typed letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 10.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, Taipei 4/7/[1959], (3 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 10.04)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 10/7/1959, (1 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 10.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, Taipei 13/[7]/[1959], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 10.05)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 22/1/1960, (1 page, typed letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 11.01)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei [n.d.]/1/1960, (2 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 11.01)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 9/2/1960, (1 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 11.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 16/2/1960, (2 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 11.03)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, Taipei 16/2/[1960], (3 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 11.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Kao-hsiung 17/2/1960, (1 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 11.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, Kao-hsiung, 7/3/1960, (1 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 11.05)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, Taipei 24/3/1960, (1 page, typed letter (copy) ) (Box 01, Folder 11.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, Kao-hsiung 5/4/1960, (1 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 11.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, Taipei 17/4/1960, (1 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 11.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 6/5/l960, (1 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 11.05)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, [n.p.] 16/5/1960, (1 page, typed letter (copy) ) (Box 01, Folder 11.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 19/5/1960, (1 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 11.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 28/5/1960, (1 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 11.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 11/7/1960, (1 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 11.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 15/7/1960, (1 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 11.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 18/10/1960, (1 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 11.05)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Peter H. L. Chang, [n.p.] 24/12/1960, (1 page, typed letter (copy) ) (Box 01, Folder 11.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 30/6/[1966], (4 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.01)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, Taipei [n.d.], (2 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Taiwan] [n.d.], (2 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p., n.d.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p., n.d.], (1 leaf, manuscript letter ) (Box 01, Folder 12.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p., n.d.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p., n.d.], (2 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 06.03)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 20/[n.m.]/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.03)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 31/[n.m.]/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.03)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 14/1/[n.y.], (2 page autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 20/1/[n.y.], (½ page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 21/1/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 2/2/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 3/2/[n.y.], (2 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.04)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Jingshang]7/3/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 16/3/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 22/3/[n.y.], (2 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 27/3[ ny], (1 leaf autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 30/3/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 12.05)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Jingshang] 19/4/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 13.01)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 5/5/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 13.01)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 14/6/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 13.01)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 24/6/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 13.01)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 15/8[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 13.01)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 23/8/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 13.01)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 1/9/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 13.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [Jingshang] 5/9/[n.y.], (2 page, autograph letter (draft) ) (Box 01, Folder 13.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 20/10/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 13.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 28/10/[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 13.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 8/11[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 13.02)
    - Chang, Peter H. L. To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 29/11[n.y.], (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 13.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. Chang, [n.p., n.d.], (1 autograph card ) (Box 01, Folder 14.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. Chang, [n.p., n.d.], (5 manuscript cards ) (Box 01, Folder 14.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. and Edith Chao Chang, [Taiwan] 30/11/m51[1962], (1 receipt ) (Box 01, Folder 14.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. and Edith Chao Chang, [Taiwan] 11/30/m57[1968] (Box 01, Folder 14.03)
      [1 receipt]
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. and Edith Chao Chang, [Taiwan] 5/12/m57[1968], (1 receipt ) (Box 01, Folder 14.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. and Edith Chao Chang, [Taiwan] 28/9/m58[1969], (1 receipt ) (Box 01, Folder 14.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. and Edith Chao Chang, [Taiwan] 14/12/M58[1969], (1 receipt ) (Box 01, Folder 14.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. and Edith Chao Chang, [n.p.] 16/2/1970, (1 card ) (Box 01, Folder 14.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. and Edith Chao Chang, [Taiwan] 30/6/m62[1973], (1 receipt ) (Box 01, Folder 14.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. and Edith Chao Chang, [n.p.] 30/9/1978, (1 page, typed letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 13.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. and Edith Chao Chang, New York 21/3/1981, (1 page, telegram(with a calling card) ) (Box 01, Folder 13.03)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Mr. and Mrs. Peter H. L. Chang, New York 12/10/M74 [1985], (1 page, telegram ) (Box 01, Folder 13.03)
    - Chang, Mei-ling Soong [Enter description] (Box 01, Folder 13.04)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Mr. and Mrs. Peter H. L. Chang, [n.p.] 30/3/[n.y.], (1 page, manuscript letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 13.05)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Mr. and Mrs. Peter H. L. Chang, [n.p.] 24/4/[n.y.], (1 page, manuscript letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 13.05)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Mr. and Mrs. Peter H. L. Chang, [n.p., n.d.], (1 page, manuscript letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 13.05)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. and Edith Chao Chang, [n.p., n.d.], (2 cards ) (Box 01, Folder 14.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. and Edith Chao Chang, [n.p., n.d.], (2 cards ) (Box 01, Folder 14.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To H. L. and Edith Chao Chang, [Taiwan] [n.d.], (3 receipts ) (Box 01, Folder 14.03)
    - Chang, Edith Chao To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 8/7/1961, (1 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 14.01)
    - Chang, Edith Chao To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 11/4/1962, (1/2 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 14.01)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Edith Chang, [n.p., n.d.], (1 card with envelope ) (Box 01, Folder 14.01)
    - Chang, Edith Chao To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 4/9/1962, (1/2 page, typed letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 14.01)
    - Chang, Edith Chao To Mei-ling Soong Chiang, [n.p.] 13/7/1962, (1 page, autograph letter draft) (Box 01, Folder 14.01)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Edith Chao Chang, [n.p.] 22/12/1983, (1 card ) (Box 01, Folder 14.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Edith Chao Chang, [n.p., n.d.]/[n.m.]/1984, (1 card ) (Box 01, Folder 14.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Edith Chao Chang, [Taipei] 30/8/1988, (2 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 14.01)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Edith Chao Chang, [Taipei] [n.d.], (1 page, autograph letter signed ) (Box 01, Folder 14.01)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Edith Chao Chang, [n.p., n.d.], (1 card ) (Box 01, Folder 14.02)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling Soong To Edith Chao Chang, [n.p., n.d.], (2 manuscript cards ) (Box 01, Folder 14.02)